In the previous video, we've or previous
videos, we talked a lot about local
storage and session storage and those
are just two built-in functions. But
sometimes you want to use functions that
are not builtin. For example, let's say
you were working with this fetch
function and you said you wanted to
fetch a piece of advice. In order to do
that, you had to fetch it and then you
had to turn it into JSON and then you
had to log it. Or written using async
aait, you had to fetch it, turn it into
JSON and then log it. Um, and maybe that
felt like a lot of steps to you. Also,
if you wanted to do a post request, then
you had to add in extra data here. And I
actually didn't show you this, but um
you could say method is post. And it was
kind of a pain to set that up, which is
why I didn't show it to you because in
this video, we're going to talk about a
library that makes all of that easier.
So, this library is, drum roll please,
Axios. So, Axios makes it so that you
can write um you can say axios.get to do
a get request, you can do axios.post to
do a post request. Um and instead of
having to take the response and turn it
into JSON data, it automatically does
that for you. So, if you want to know
how to use this magic thing, well, you
first have to bring it in. So, it's just
code that someone else wrote. And in
order to get the code someone else wrote
onto your computer, you have to tell it
where that code is. So, just like you
can have a script tag that points to
your own external script file, um, like
if I made a script.js over here, you can
have a script tag that points to someone
else's external JS file. So, this is
saying go out to the content delivery
network and find the Axios library.
Once you've done that, you can now use
the Axios keyword. So, you can say
axios.get
and then we can put in https/
API advice slip.com/advice
and then axios.get returns a promise. So
we can say then and inside of that
promise it returns an object with a data
attribute. But let's just take the
result and log it.
So if we save this and I'm actually
going to comment out that and comment
out this fetch. So the only thing
running is our axios.get.
And if we come over here, we can see
that it returns data. And if we open up
data, data actually contains our data.
We don't then have to convert it into
JavaScript and wait for that to happen
using um this asynchronous.json
function. So what we could do is rather
than just receiving this response
object, we could dstructure it into
data. So we're saying take the object,
destructure it, just grab the data
attribute, and then let's log out the
data. So now if we do that we can log
out our slip directly.
So writing this in async weight will
actually show you how many less lines it
is. So what I'm going to do is I'm going
to comment this out and I'm going to
write it below. So I'll say let um data
equal axios.get
httpsi.advicelip.comadvice.
And I need to await that. And once I'm
done, I can console.log the data. And so
I've dropped off this entire line just
by um switching over to Axios. Um, and
I'll show you in the next videos how you
can use Axios for the other parts of
CRUD.